(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-20T01:56:54.400541",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
うん、えっと...
Um, let's see...
席はこのあたりでいいのかな？
I wonder if these seats around here are good?
よっこい、っと。
Heave-ho.
今年もミュージカルテイストなのかな？
I wonder if it's going to have a musical taste this year too?
わくわく！
So exciting!
こんばんは、どどどん！
Good evening, dododon!
ここ、座ってもいい？
Can I sit here?
よーや、お揃いで。
Yo-ya, all together.
今日はアキロゼの誕生日だから、一緒に祝ってやろうじゃないか、うんうん！
Today is Akirose's birthday, so let's celebrate together, yeah yeah!
やっほー！
Yahoo!
そういえばアキロゼ先輩、誕生日前にシプロに全然インしてなかったんだよね。
Come to think of it, Akirose-senpai wasn't logging into C2 at all before her birthday.
練習頑張っててってことだから、楽しみだね！
That means she was working hard on practice, so I'm looking forward to it!
アンシスのバカたれども、よーお揃いで！
You fools of Ansys, all gathered together!
いやいやいや、今日はポルカモデルだから応援しててな。
No no no, today is Polka model, so cheer us on.
うんうん。
Yeah yeah.
がんばれ、ポルカ！
Do your best, Polka!
いや、ロボ子さん？
Wait, Roboco-san?
あんたもデルガ王でしょうが！待機場所ここじゃないから！
You're also a Delsuga King, aren't you! The waiting area isn't here!
ぽんがぽーん...
Ponga-pon...
はあ、行ったな。
Haah, she went.
行ったね。
She did.
もうすぐ始まりそうだけど、間に合うかな？
It looks like it's about to start soon, will we make it?
まったく、ごちゃごちゃ煩い野郎だ。我々は楽しませてもらうだけなのだよ。
Good grief, what noisy nuisances. We're just here to be entertained.
よし。
Alright.
Once upon a time, there was a girl named Dorothy.
She's lost her parents by death when innocent infant
and gets weary of life with her aunt and uncle, too ordinary.
This lovable girl is dreaming of adventure.
in an extraordinary Wonderland.
Music Wizard of OZ by OSTER project
果てしなく広がるこの空の下僕らを導くのはあのメロディ
Endlessly spreading under this sky, guiding us is that melody
遥かな時間を越えて繋がるどんなときも心は覚えているから
Connecting across distant times, my heart remembers no matter when
いつものように目が覚めると
When I wake up like always
いつものように庭には鳥に餌をあげるの
Feeding the birds in the garden like always
いつものように焦げたトーストと
With burnt toast like always
いつものように叔母さんガミガミ叔父さんブツブツもうたくさんよ
Auntie nagging and uncle mumbling like always, I've had enough
ああ私だっていつか絵本みたいな冒険がしてみたいの
Ah, I too want to have an adventure like in a picture book someday
悪い魔女とか魔法使いとか考えるだけでゾクゾクしちゃう
Thinking about evil witches or wizards just makes me thrill with fear
ああこのままどこかへ飛んでいきたいわ竜巻とかで...
Ah, I want to fly away somewhere like this, by a tornado or something...
気が付けばそこは小人の国
Before I knew it, it was the land of dwarfs
悲しみは笑いましょう
Let's laugh away the sorrow
生きるってマリオネット
Living life like a marionette
心臓がスイングしたら
If your heart starts to swing
琴線はいかが？
How about your heartstrings?
1・2・2・1・2・2
Un, deux, deux, un, deux, deux
1・2・2・3
Un, deux, deux, trois
私うまく踊れないわ
I really can't dance well
痛みも 恨みも 悲しみも
All the pain, resentment, and sorrow
混ぜて（混ぜて） こねて（こねて）
Mix it (mix it), knead it (knead it)
おやすみのキス
Say good night with a kiss
シャル・ウィ・ダンス？ 踊りましょう
Shall we dance? Let's dance
絶望 欲望 this is the life!
Despair and desire, this is the life!
shadow life!
余計なこと考えないで
Don't think about unnecessary things
ひとつになりましょう
Let's become one together
いいな（いいな） いいな（いいな）
How nice (how nice), how nice (how nice)
人間って 人間って いいな
Being human, being human, so nice!
泣きたいのに笑えちゃう
Wanting to cry, but I end up laughing
人生ってピエロ
Life is like a clown
本当の心隠して
Hiding my true feelings
笑うフリをするの
Putting on a smiling face
1・2・2・1・2・2
Un, deux, deux, un, deux, deux
1・2・2・3
Un, deux, deux, trois
私うまく生きれないわ
I really can't live my life right
本音も ウソも 不安も
True feelings, lies, and anxiety
溶かして（溶かして） 蓋して（蓋して）
Melt it (melt it), cover it up (cover it up)
おやすみなさい
Good night
シャル・ウィ・ドリーム？ 夢見ましょう
Shall we dream? Let's dream
寝ても覚めても this is the life!
Sleeping or waking, this is the life!
shadow life!
いやなこと ぜんぶぜんぶ忘れましょう
Forget all the bad things, every single one of them
シャル・ウィ・ダンス？ 不器用でも
Shall we dance? Even if we're clumsy
あがいて もがいて this is the life!
Struggling and writhing, this is the life!
shadow step?
余計なこと考えないで
Don't think about unnecessary things
ステップを踏み鳴らせ！
Stamp your feet to the beat!
シャル・ウィ・スマイル？ 今だけは
Shall we smile? Just for now
一緒に笑ってみませんか
Won't you smile together with me?
shadow dance!
今だけはぜんぶ忘れて
For now, forget everything
一緒に飛びましょう
Let's jump together
シャル・ウィ・ダンス？ 踊りましょう
Shall we dance? Let's dance
絶望 欲望 this is the life!
Despair and desire, this is the life!
shadow life!
余計なこと考えないで
Don't think about unnecessary things
ひとつになりましょう
Let's become one together
シャル・ウィ・スマイル？ 今だけは
Shall we smile? Just for now
一緒に笑ってみませんか
Won't you smile together with me?
shadow dance!
今だけはぜんぶ忘れて
For now, forget everything
一緒に飛びましょう
Let's jump together
シャル・ウィ・ダンス？ 踊りましょう
Shall we dance? Let's dance
絶望 欲望 this is the life!
Despair and desire, this is the life!
shadow life!
余計なこと考えないで
Don't think about unnecessary things
ひとつになりましょう
Let's become one together
いいな（いいな） いいな（いいな）
How nice (how nice), how nice (how nice)
人間って 人間って いいな
Being human, being human, so nice!
いいな（いいな） いいな（いいな）
How nice (how nice), how nice (how nice)
人間って 人間って いいな
Being human, being human, so nice!
いいな（いいな） いいな（いいな）
How nice (how nice), how nice (how nice)
人間って 人間って いいな
Being human, being human, so nice!
1・2・2・1・2・2
Un, deux, deux, un, deux, deux
1・2・2・3
Un, deux, deux, trois
shadow! shadow!
1・2・2・1・2・2
Un, deux, deux, un, deux, deux
1・2・2・3
Un, deux, deux, trois
shadow! shadow!
いつか君が瞳に灯す愛の光が
Someday, the light of love you set in your eyes
時を超えて
will transcend time
滅び急ぐ世界の夢を
and surely shatter a dream of the world
確実に一つ壊そう
that rushes toward ruin.
躊躇いを飲み干して
Swallow down your hesitation,
君が望むモノは何?
what is it that you desire?
こんな欲深い憧れの行方に
On the path of such greedy yearning,
儚い明日はあるの?
is there a fleeting tomorrow?
子どもの頃夢に見てた
Like the ancient magic
古の魔法のように
I dreamed of as a child,
闇さえ砕く力で
with power to shatter even the darkness,
微笑む君に会いたい
I want to meet your smiling self.
怯えるこの手の中には
What I hold in these trembling hands
手折られた花の勇気
is the courage of plucked flowers.
想いだけが頼る全て
My feelings alone are all I rely on,
光を呼び覚ます
a wish that summons
願い
the light.
いつか君も誰かの為に
Someday, you too might wish
強い力を望むのだろう
for great power for someone's sake.
愛が胸を捉えた夜に
In the night when love gripped your heart,
未知の言葉が生まれて来る
unknown words are born.
迷わずに行けるなら
If I can go on without hesitation,
心が砕けてもいいわ
I don't mind if my heart shatters.
いつも目の前の哀しみに
To always face the sorrow
立ち向かう為の
right before my eyes,
呪文が欲しい
I want a spell.
君はまだ夢見る記憶
You are still a dreaming memory,
私は眠らない明日
I am a sleepless tomorrow.
二人が出会う奇跡を
To seize the miracle
勝ち取る為に進むの
of our meeting, I press forward.
怯えるこの手の中には
What I hold in these trembling hands
手折られた花の刃
is the blade of plucked flowers.
想いだけが生きる全て
My feelings alone are all I live for,
心に振りかざす
a wish brandished
願い
within my heart.
囚われた太陽の輝く
The shining of the captive sun—
不思議の国の本が好きだった頃
back when I loved books of wonderland,
願いはきっと叶うと
I believed the fairy tales
教えるお伽噺を
that taught wishes would come true,
信じた
believing them.
静かに咲き乱れていた
Blooming wildly in the quiet,
古の魔法優しく
ancient magic gently whispered
世界を変える力が
that the power to change the world
その手にあると叫ぶ
lies right in those hands.
終わらない夢を見よう
Let us dream an endless dream
君と行く時の中で
in the time we share together.
想いだけが生きる全て
My feelings alone are all I live for,
命を作るのは
and what creates life
願い
is this wish.
突然現れた
Suddenly appearing,
不機嫌なロボット
a moody robot.
油を差したら
Once I oiled it up,
ゆっくり踊り出して
it slowly started dancing,
めでためでたさぴの
how wonderful...
プログラムされた
Even if it's a programmed dance
ダンスなら完璧に
and I dance it so perfectly,
踊っているのに
(dancing it so perfectly,)
あなたのダンスにはハートがないと怒られるの
they tell me my dance has no heart and scold me.
デジタルの檻の中
Inside the digital cage,
与えられた言葉だけじゃ
just with the words given to us,
わからないことばかり
there's so much I don't understand.
だけど悲し楽しい
But though it's sad yet fun,
それなら一緒に
if so, let's search
探しに行こう
for it together!
君の心
Your heart—
願わば願い事を叶えてくれる
granting whatever wish you desire,
不思議なミュージックウィズアウト
a mysterious music wizard!
デジタルの檻の中
Inside the digital cage,
鮮やかに彩ってたり
vibrantly coloring things,
この胸で感じる時代
feeling it in this chest of mine,
もっと自由私達のメタリック
more freely, our metallic selves—
あの道を辿って
following that path
ミュージックウィザードの方向へ
toward the music wizard!
お願いごとはなに
What is your wish?
さあ来い
Come on,
この元を探そう
let's find the source.
さあ歌声が空からに
Now let the song echo to the sky,
エメラルドの街へ行こう
let's go to the Emerald City!
行こう
Let's go!
頼んだ！
I asked for it!
街を見てる
Looking at the town
歌おう
Let's sing!
聞いてくれ 俺たちの悲しい物語
Listen to our sad story.
ライオンなのに
Even though I'm a lion,
even though I'm a lion...
お肉が怖くて食べらんない
I'm scared of meat and can't eat it!
今日も狩りへ行くのさ
Today too, I'm going hunting!
キャベツニンジンブロッコリー
Cabbage, carrots, broccoli,
レタスネギトマト
lettuce, green onions, tomatoes...
生まれてこの方ベジタリアン
Vegetarian since birth!
朝ごはん ポテトサラダ
Breakfast: potato salad.
昼ごはん ポテトサラダ
Lunch: potato salad.
晩ごはん ポテトサラダ
Dinner: potato salad.
特典はもちろん豆腐
And of course, the special is tofu!
お願いごとはなに
What is your wish?
その心と勇気さ
That heart and courage!
さあみんなで踊りあって
Now everyone dance together
エメラルドの街へ
to the Emerald City!
行こう
Let's go!
loneliness, you're tied around my wrist
when all i ever wanted was this
yeah, all i ever wanted was this
sleepless nights, always seem to lose these fights
building on my thoughts like bricks
but nothing in my blood says quit
when the lights go out, and i'm all by myself in the darkness
when the lights go out, i hear my heart beating the hardest
oh, i was born to break these chains
like a spark before the flames
watch me light a fire, fire in my soul
yeah, i can feel it in my bones
like a dream ready to explode
watch me light a fire
battle scars, lead me through the night like stars
and all i ever wanted was this
yeah, all i ever wanted was this
out of bounds, when every single wall comes down
i'll be standing on the edge of greatness
oh, i was born to break these chains
like a spark before the flames
watch me light a fire, fire in my soul
yeah, i can feel it in my bones
like a dream ready to explode
watch me light a fire, fire in my soul
fire, fire, fire, fire, fire, fire
Watch me light a fire,
fire in my soul
When the lights go out
And I'm all by myself in the darkness
I hear my heart beating the hardest
Oh, I was born to break these chains
Like a spark before the flames
Watch me light a fire,
fire in my soul
Yeah, I can feel it in my bones
Like a dream ready to explode
Watch me light a fire,
fire in my soul
照らし出して！ グリーンライツ
Shine a light! Greenlights,
広がる未来を
expanding into the future
きっと いつか キミを照らすまで
Surely, until one day I illuminate you
改めて言うことでもないけど
It's not like I'm saying this anew, but
今だからこそ言わせて
Let me say it precisely because it's now
あの日キミが見つけてくれること
The fact that you found me that day
なんとなくだく予感してたんだ
I somehow had a hunch about it
走り出したキミにもっと チカラをあげたくて
Wanting to give even more power to you who started running
ずっと前にココロ決めたんだ
I decided in my heart long ago
照らし出して！ グリーンライツ
Shine a light! Greenlights,
遥かな未来を
To the distant future
きっと いつか キミを照らすまで
Surely, until one day I illuminate you
今までもいつまでも隣に居たいのは
Wanting to stay by your side until now and forever
輝いたキミの顔間近で見たいから
Because I want to see your shining face up close
言葉時は気まぐれでなかなか
Words are sometimes fickle and somehow
この世界は変わらないけど
This world doesn't change, but
もしキミが持ってるその魔法で
If with that magic you possess
新しい世界を作れるとしたら？
You could create a new world?
なんてね 言ってみただけ
Just kidding, I was just saying
そんなの本当に出る訳がないでしょ！
That can't possibly really happen!
「好き」をもっと信じるのさ
Believe more in "I like you"
何度転んでもキミはキミのやり方でいいのさ
No matter how many times you fall, your way is fine
照らし出して！ グリーンライツ
Shine a light! Greenlights,
手をつなぐ未来を
To the future where we hold hands
きっと いつか キミを照らすまで
Surely, until one day I illuminate you
こんな夜には隣で泣いていいよ
On such a night, it's okay to cry beside me
二人だけの秘密も嬉しいんだよ
Even our secret just between us makes me happy
走り出したキミにもっと チカラをあげたくて
Wanting to give even more power to you who started running
ずっと前にココロ決めたんだ
I decided in my heart long ago
照らし出して！ グリーンライツ
Shine a light! Greenlights,
遥かな未来を
To the distant future
きっと いつか キミを照らすまで
Surely, until one day I illuminate you
振り返ると遠く手を描いてくれるキミも
Even you, waving from far away when looking back
この先のどこかで出会えるキミも
Even you, whom I can meet somewhere ahead
誰にも真似できないあなたを抱きしめて
Embrace yourself, whom no one else can imitate
虹色の輝き間近で見たいから！
Because I want to see the rainbow radiance up close!
振り返ると遠く手を描いてくれるキミも
Even you, waving from far away when looking back
この先のどこかで出会えるキミも
Even you, whom I can meet somewhere ahead
誰にも真似できないあなただけ抱きしめて
Embrace only yourself, whom no one else can imitate
虹色の輝き間近で見たいから
Because I want to see the rainbow radiance up close
息を吸って吐くだけじゃ
Just inhaling and exhaling,
人形と同じでしょ？
aren't you just like a doll?
何のために生き てるの？
What are you living for?
失わないで Only your blazing heart
Don't lose it, only your blazing heart.
夢は叶うものなんて ただの綺麗事だけど
"Dreams come true" is just a platitude, but
あきらめるくらいなら 選んじゃいけないよ
if you're going to give up, you shouldn't choose it.
Such a narrow and steep road
さあさあその手を挙げろ
come on, raise your hands!
GARNiDELiA musicに もっと委ねて
Surrender yourself more to GARNiDELiA's music,
さあさあ大声上げろ
come on, raise your voices!
こんな世界にさ revolutionを
Bring a revolution to a world like this!
なんて言われても 何度倒れても
No matter what they say, no matter how many times I fall,
貫いたprideが 目の前のキセキと
the pride I've upheld led me to the miracle
出会わせてくれた
right before my eyes.
幼い顔でほら 下手くそに笑うから
With a childish, awkward smile,
伸ばしたくなる手を 抑えるのが大変で
holding back my reaching hand is so hard.
少し濡れたまつ毛も 手の平の温度も
Even your slightly damp lashes and palm warmth
隠しながら 抱えながら 見ていた
I watched, hiding and holding them inside.
君を知らない誰かになれたら きっと楽になれるのに
If I could become someone who doesn't know you, it'd be easier,
抱きしめたいよ もう嘘はつきたくないんだよ
but I want to hold you, I don't want to lie anymore.
その温もりを教えてよ
Teach me that warmth.
叫ぶ声は胸の中で 君に伝えることもできないまま
My shouting voice remains in my heart, unable to reach you,
溢れていくよ ねえ 聞こえていますか
overflowing... Hey, can you hear me?
君は何も求めず 何も語らず
You ask for nothing, you speak of nothing,
渡しかけたこの声は 滲んで消えた
and the voice I tried to hand you blurred and faded.
見えない心も 触れられない身体も
An invisible heart, an untouchable body—
知りたくて 感じたくて 待っていた
I wanted to know, wanted to feel, and waited.
虹なんて 見えなくてもいいから
Even if we can't see a rainbow, it's fine,
雨は降らないでと 君は笑う
you smile, asking for no rain.
抱きしめたいよ この腕で守りたいんだよ
I want to hold you, I want to protect you in these arms,
だからその心を分けてよ
so please share that heart with me.
叫ぶ声は胸の中で 君に伝えることもできないまま
My shouting voice is in my heart, unable to reach you,
溢れていく
overflowing.
イヤホン分け合って 聴いた流行りの曲
The trending song we listened to sharing earphones,
触れる肩も その温度も全部が愛しくて
every shoulder touch and every bit of warmth was so dear.
だけど言葉には出せない でも戻れない
Yet I can't put it into words, but I can't go back either.
どうにでもなれと思うのに 神様 どうか二人を結んでください
Though I think whatever happens happens, God, please bind us together
解けないように強く強く
so strongly and tightly that it can never be undone,
これから先も二人ずーっと
from now on, just the two of us, forever.
叫ぶ声は胸の中で 君に伝えることもできないまま 溢れていくよ ねえ 届いていますか
My shouting voice remains in my heart... Hey, can you hear me?
石の砦に 鳴り響くミュージック
Music echoing through the stone fortress,
憂いを映した 孤独なギター
a lonely guitar reflecting our sorrow.
All alone without you ひとりきりのコンサートホール
All alone without you, in a solo concert hall.
誰も消やしないのさ
Nobody's erasing it,
美しい色がない世界で
in a world without beautiful colors.
私が消えない物に 意味などあるものか
What meaning is there in things that don't fade away?
So please listen to my sounds!
それなら 僕たちと一緒に 友達を探しに行こう
If so, let's go together to search for friends,
ミュージックウィザードのもとへ
to the Music Wizard!
一人では奇跡は起こせないから
Because miracles can't happen alone,
みんなで行こう
let's all go together
エメラルドの街へ
to the Emerald City!
さあ 魔法のギターで
Come on, with our magic guitar
僕らの願いを奏でていま
play our wishes right now!
ほら 耳を澄ませば 聞こえるでしょう
Hey, if you listen closely, you'll hear it,
誰の中にも隠れてる魔法
the magic hidden inside everyone.
誰もが生まれ持った喜びをさあ見失って
The joy everyone was born with, come on, let's find it
答えはそこにあるの 魔法のギターを
and the answer is right there, play the magic guitar!
想いようたにできるのは
What can turn feelings into song
僕らが知恵をモテいるから
is because we possess wisdom.
好きな歌を口ずさむとはかなくするの
Humming your favorite song makes it fleeting...
果てしなく広がるこの空の下
Underneath this endlessly expanding sky,
僕らを導くのはあのメロディー
the one guiding us is that melody.
大きな声を上げて 歌を歌えるのは
Being able to raise our voices loud and sing
僕らが勇気を持っているから
is because we hold courage within us.
そして声を合わせて
And by bringing our voices together,
よろこびをわかり合える それが友達
we can share in each other's joy—that's what friends are.
ありのままの自分の中に息づいてる大切なたからもの
The precious treasure living deep within our true selves,
拾い上げて 静かに凍える
picking it up, even when quietly freezing,
それが奇跡 それがミュージー
that is a miracle, that is music.
最後はあなたの願いをきかせて
Finally, let me hear your wish,
思いのままに夢を描いて
and paint your dreams just as you feel.
ねぇ 私気づいたの わくわくする黄金よりも
Hey, I realized... even more than shimmering gold,
どんな素晴らしい夢よりも かけがえのないものがあるの
there is something more irreplaceable than any wonderful dream.
にくたらしくなる時もあるけど
Though there are times when we get annoyed with each other,
私の願いは ただ一つ家族に会いたい
my only wish is to see my family again.
あなたの愛した あの歌を
That song you loved so much,
あなたを愛する あの人も
and that person who loves you as well,
きっとどこかで 口ずさんでるから
are surely humming it somewhere out there.
耳をすまして
So listen closely.
私の愛する この歌が 私の愛する あの人と
This song of mine, filled with love, connecting me with the one I love,
私をいつでもつなぎ合わせてくれる奇跡のミュージー
is the miracle of music that always links us together.
果てしなく広がる この空の下
Underneath this endlessly expanding sky,
僕らを導くのは あのメロディー
the melody that guides us onward,
遥かなる時間を 超えて繋がる
connecting across distant expanses of time.
どんなときも心は覚えてるよ
No matter what, my heart remembers it all.
奇跡のミュージー
The miracle of music...
生まれたて30秒で最初に聞いた言葉は当たり前にりゃ覚えてないけど
Though I naturally don't remember the first words I heard after birth,
嬉しかったはず
I'm sure I was happy.
今友達大事なことは変わってないていうか中身は変わっていまですので
Friends are still important; our inner selves have evolved since then.
経済のアンテナを光らせた それが超キュートな あの頃だって知っていたり
Keeping our economic antennas sharp—we knew how super cute those days were.
手を繋いで何を見てるの 私に付き合ってくれるの好き
Holding hands, what are you looking at? You're willing to hang out with me—I love that.
私の一番可愛いところに気づいてくれるの きみが一番すごいすごいよ
Noticing the cutest things about me—you're simply amazing, incredible!
あれ気付いちゃいましたか？
Have you noticed yet?
そして君が知ってる私が一番かわいいの
And you know that I'm the cutest of all.
私もそれに気付いた
I've realized it too.
だからそれかわいい あれかわいいなんて
So don't say things like "that's cute" or "this is cute,"
誰かわいい それかわいいなんて
or "who is cute" or "that's cute"—
言わないで 私以外なんてやだ
don't say anyone but me, I hate that!
ってありえない
As if that's possible!
私気付いちゃいました
I've realized it!
毎日何十秒褒められまくったお菓子は
Sweets praised for dozens of seconds every day
他よりちょっと甘くなるって前に聞いたような
get a little sweeter than others, or so I heard before.
さすがにそれなんか変だけど私は言われたいタイプでして
That's a bit strange, but I'm the type who wants to be told that,
もっとわかりやすくしていいんだよ
so you can make it easier to understand, you know?
お待ちしてます（おねがい！）
I'm waiting (Please!)
何しててもどんな顔見せてても
No matter what I'm doing or what face I'm making,
いつも超キュートだって確信してるのは
I'm convinced I'm always super cute—
なんだかさ知らなかったタイプの運命の
somehow, it's a destiny of a type I never knew.
出会いは無理ごめん逆でもそれより楽しいよ
Meeting you is impossible, sorry! But even the reverse is more fun!
ねぇねぇねぇ
Hey, hey, hey!
私のいちばん、かわいいところをよく見てる
You're watching my cutest side so closely,
そんな君が本当に超ラッキーな人すぎる
making you a truly super lucky person!
そして君が何年たってもそう惚れられるように
And so that you'll fall in love with me no matter how many years pass,
私はそれに気付いた
I've realized it.
会えないときもどんな表情してることか
Even when we can't meet, I end up imagining
気持ち悪いから想像しちゃうから
what kind of expression you're making, because it's creepy how much I do!
それかわいいあれかわいいよって
Saying "that's cute, this is cute,"
ほんとにかわいいでいて
please really stay cute for me.
私のいちばん、かわいいところに気付いてる
You've noticed my cutest side,
そんな君が一番すごいすごいよ凄すぎる
making you the most amazing, incredible person ever!
そして君が知ってる私が一番かわいいの
And you know that I'm the cutest of all.
私はそれに気付いた
I've realized it.
私のいちばん、かわいいところをよく見てる
You're watching my cutest side so closely,
そんな君が本当に超ラッキーな人すぎる
making you a truly super lucky person!
そして君が何年たってもそう惚れられるように
And so that you'll fall in love with me no matter how many years pass,
私はそれに気付いた
I've realized it.
私のいちばん、かわいいところに気付いてる
You've noticed my cutest side,
そんな君が一番すごいすごいよ凄すぎる
making you the most amazing, incredible person ever!
そして君が知ってる私が一番かわいいの
And you know that I'm the cutest of all.
私はそれに気付いた
I've realized it.
だからそれかわいいあれかわいいなんて
So don't say things like "that's cute" or "this is cute,"
誰かわいいそれかわいいなんて言わないで私以外なんてやだ
or "who's cute"—don't say anyone but me, I hate that!
なんてありえない
As if that's possible!
あー、はぁー...！ アキロゼ生誕祭2023を見てくれてるみんなー！
Ah, hah... Everyone watching Aki Rosenthal's 2023 Birthday Festival!
見えてる？聞こえてるー？ あろーな！
Can you see me? Can you hear me? Aloha!
やっと喋れるー！
I can finally speak!
今回も盛りだくさんだったね！
There was so much packed into this again!
ということで、今回のライブは去年に引き続めまして大好きなースタープロジェクトさんの大恐魔法使いのミュージカルをやらさせていただきましたー！
So, continuing from last year, for this live performance, we performed a musical by my favorite Star Project called "Oozora Magic User"!
素敵な曲を... ありがとうございます！
Such wonderful songs... Thank you so much!
そして今回のライブにぴったりのステージセットをこんなに可愛く作ってもらいましたー！ めっちゃかわいいでしょ？
And they made such a cute stage set that fits this live performance! Isn't it super cute?
ぜひね、アーカイブとかでもじっくりいろんなところを見てくれたら
If you take your time and check out all the details in the archive too,
めっっちゃ制作陣も喜びます！ もちろんアキロゼも喜びます！
the production team will be so, so happy! Of course Aki Rosenthal will be too!
ぜひね、そんな感想とかもいっぱい見たいので、今日の配信の感想や可愛いスクショ、短い動画とか、ハッシュタグをつけていっぱいツイートしてください！
And since I want to see lots of your impressions, please tweet tons with hashtags for the live impressions, cute screenshots, and short videos!
アキロゼめっっちゃ巡回します！見ます！よろしくね！
Aki Rosenthal will totally check them all out! See you!
このハッシュタグは、こちら！ これつけると見やすいのでぜひぜひつけてくださーい！YouTubeのコメントもよろしくねー！
Here is the hashtag! Adding this makes it easy to find, so please definitely use it! And please leave YouTube comments too!
ひと息ついたところで
Right after catching my breath...
ここで！
Right here!
重大発表、イェーイ！
A major announcement, yay!
なんと、アキローゼンタール
And get this, Aki Rosenthal's...
オリジナル楽曲第4弾発売決定！
4th original song release is decided!
それでは、先行ひろめしちゃいます。聞いてください、
Without further ado, we'll preview it. Please listen:
キミにまつわる運命事情！
Kimi ni Matsuwaru Unmei Jijō!
今日は絶好調 …そのはずでした過去形
Today is going great... or at least that's how it should've been.
天気予報 ド外れ ドア閉まるバス 憂鬱 Monday
Weather forecast totally off, bus doors closing, gloomy Monday.
なんて不条理 文句誰行き? 八つ当たりは
How absurd. Who to complain to? Taking it out on others is...
問題外 どうしようもないコト 多すぎ Everyday 現実の手強い
...out of the question. There's nothing I can do, too much Everyday, reality is tough.
だけど試練の向こうへ ため息ついてここから
But beyond the trials, sighing from here,
立ち上がれたらまた なにかが始まる
if I can stand back up, something new will begin.
Let's get it going now! がむしゃら気味に どこへだって
Let's get it going now! Recklessly heading anywhere,
繰り出して 胸張って 楽しもう Up・Down
venturing out, puffing my chest out, let's enjoy it Up Down!
Say everyone, going now! 蹴っ飛ばしちゃえよ ああいう そういう 波乱万丈
Say everyone, going now! Kick it away, such turbulent times,
大体の運命 変えてくのは自分だって
most of our fate is changed by none other than ourselves.
――キミは知ってる
...You know that.
電車で割り込み コンビニで傘無くなった
Cutting in line on the train, umbrella lost at the convenience store.
ジリジリ減っていってる ハートの残機 あとどれくらい?
My remaining heart lives are ticking away, how many are left?
辻褄合っていなくていい 悲劇の1秒先で
It doesn't have to make sense, just one second past tragedy,
思いきり笑ったら いい日に格上げ!
if I can laugh with all my might, it gets upgraded to a good day!
Let's get it going now! 顔上げてほら ありのままのステップで
Let's get it going now! Lift your head, come on, with your natural steps,
予測不能 未来へ踏み出して
step out into an unpredictable future.
Say everyone, going now! 吹き飛ばしちゃえ 冴えない 浮かない 顔した
Say everyone, going now! Blow away that dull, gloomy look,
今日なんて全部 自分だけがそう出来るって
knowing that you alone can change a day like today.
キミは知ってる
You know that.
I will try it again! 分かってるはずさ
I will try it again! I'm sure you know.
I will try it again! ひらかれるはずさ
I will try it again! It's bound to open up.
今はまだ遠い そんな景色 怖くても 眩しくても この手で掴めるまで...
That scenery is still far away, but whether frightening or dazzling, until I grasp it with these hands...
Let's get it going now! がむしゃら気味に どこへだって 繰り出して 胸張って 楽しもう Up・Down
Let's get it going now! Recklessly heading anywhere, venturing out, puffing my chest out, let's enjoy it Up Down!
Say everyone, going now! めげない焦げない あきらめないで あいう そういう 波乱万丈
Say everyone, going now! Don't give up, don't burn out, such turbulent times,
大体の運命 変えてくのは自分 さあ、どうするんだ
most of our fate is changed by ourselves. Now, what will you do?
ハッピーチューンの奏で方 キミは知ってる
You know how to play a happy tune.
キミにまつわる運命事情でしたー！かわいかったかな？
That was Kimi ni Matsuwaru Unmei Jijō! Was it cute?
こちらの新曲は、今後各種ストリーミングサービスで配信が決定してます！
As for this new song, its release on various streaming services has been decided!
本日の生誕祭ではうれしい先行ひろめということで 今後の発売日はTwitterでお知らせします！
Since we premiered it early at today's birthday festival, future release dates will be announced on Twitter!
こちらの新曲は、ライブタイトルにもなっている...
This new song shares its name with the live title...
スタート ユーアー ジャーニー あなたの旅を始めよう
"Start Your Journey"—let your journey begin!
そんなふうに背中を押してくれるような曲になってます
It's a song that feels like it's pushing you forward from behind.
元気付きたいとき、テンション上げたいときとかに、いっぱい聞いてもらって、勇気をだしてくれたら嬉しいなと思います。
Whenever you need energy or want to boost your mood, I hope you listen to it a lot and find courage.
あ!Twitterでさきにお知らせするって言ったんだけど、
Oh! I said on Twitter I'd announce it earlier, but...
もう、Twitterフォローしてるよね?
You're already following me on Twitter, right?
チャンネル登録したやつ、いいよねお姉。
Channel subscription alerts are great, right?
今！今！今！チャンネル登録したやつ、いいよねお姉！
Right now! Channel subscription alerts are great!
今までの人いるよ！
There are people who've been here for a while too!
曲の感想とかも、Twitterでね、ハッシュタグをつけて聞かせてもらえるとあきちゃんも見やすいので、よろしくお願いします！
If you share your impressions of the song on Twitter with a hashtag, I'd love to read them, so please do!
そしてお待たせのグッズ紹介の！
And now, introducing the much-awaited merchandise!
アキ・ローゼンタール誕生日記念2023グッズが発売になります！
Aki Rosenthal's Birthday Commemoration 2023 merchandise is now on sale!
ライブテーマの「Start your journey あなたの旅を始めよう」という思いをぎゅっと込めた、オズの魔法使いをイメージしたグッズになっています。
It's filled with the thoughts of the live theme, "Start your journey," themed around The Wizard of Oz.
内容は、「Start your journey ポップアップアクリルスタンド」こちらじゅん先生の描き下ろしになっています！めちゃめちゃ可愛くて、ロゼ隊もジョーブズも嫉妬するペンギンもちゃっかり...旅の仲間と加わってるので、ぜひね飾って楽しんでもらえたらと思います。
The contents include the "Start your journey Pop-up Acrylic Stand," beautifully illustrated by Jun-sensei! It's super cute, featuring Rose-tai, Jobuzu, and even a jealous penguin joining as travel companions, so I hope you'll display and enjoy it.
そして、持って出かけそのまま旅に出れちゃう！ブック型ポーチ！
And a book-shaped pouch you can take right out on your travels!
そして普段使いから、ご褒美使いまでできるりんご型プレートとカトラリーセットも一緒になっています。ぜひね、おうちでもお外でも楽しんでください。
Plus an apple-shaped plate and cutlery set for everyday or special treats. Please enjoy them at home or out!
そして今回はシチュエーションボイス「もしもアキロゼと温泉デートに行ったら」、ASMRボイス「夢の中で起きたことと…」そしてASMRボイスもあります！こちらのみんなのことを持ってね、ドキドキできるようなシチュエーションボイスドラマになっているので、ぜひそちらも楽しみにしてください。
And this time, we have a situation voice "If I went on a hot spring date with Akirose," ASMR voice "What happened in a dream...", and ASMR voice drama! It's packed with heart-pounding situations, so please look forward to those too.
そしてこちら、なんとフルセット購入の方は、アキロゼ直筆のサインが...ブロマイドチェキにかかれて届いちゃうえええええええ！
And what's more, those who purchase the full set will receive a Polaroid-style bromaide with Akirose's handwritten signature! Whaaaat?!
はい、アキロゼ書きます！サイン直筆でめちゃ書きたいの！だからフルセット買ってね！
Yes, Akirose will write them! I really want to handwrite your signatures! So please buy the full set!
ちなみに、特典ボイスも付いてくるよ！やったー！そんな感じの盛りだくさんな内容なのでぜひぜひゲットしてください！はい！
By the way, bonus voice tracks are included too! Yay! It's packed with content like this, so please definitely grab it! Yay!
絶対買ってね！今がチャンスだよ！そしてもう一つお知らせがあります！
Definitely buy it! Now's your chance! And I have one more announcement!
なんと、本日この配信の後22時15分から、メンバー限定でぷちアンコールライブやっちゃいます！イエーイ！
Today, right after this stream at 22:15, we're holding a member-limited mini encore live! Yay!
メンバー限定配信では、なんとアンコール曲と今回のステージをもっとね、近い距離で紹介していけたらなと思います！可愛いスクショとかちょっとイチャイチャしたりとか楽しんでもらえたらいいなと思っているので、ぜひぜひメンバー登録のまだの人は忘れずにね！
In the member-limited stream, we'll introduce encore songs and today's stage from a closer distance! I hope you'll enjoy cute screenshots and sweet moments, so if you haven't registered as a member yet, don't forget!
今だよ！ピース！ピース！はい！ということで、それでは...
Right now! Peace! Peace! Yes! And so, now...
アキロゼ生誕祭2023！ありがとうございました！みんなのおかげで最高の誕生日になりました！ありがとう！
Aki Rosenthal Birthday Festival 2023! Thank you so much! Thanks to everyone, it was the best birthday ever! Thank you!
それでは...またね！メンバーの人...限定配信の準備だ！まだの人...今だぞ！バイバーイ！
Well then... see you later! Members... get ready for the limited stream! For those who aren't, now's the time! Bye-bye!
CAST
[Title: CAST]
OMARU POLKA
すごいね、緊張したっていうか
It was amazing, I was so nervous,
なんか、いつもとさ
you know, compared to the usual—
ね、違うじゃん？
well, it's different, right?
そう。
Yeah.
うん。それでもあの、楽しくやらせていただきました！
Even so, I had so much fun doing it!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
いや、みなさんももう本当にありがとうございましたー！
And to everyone watching, thank you so muchー!
はい、ありがと、プルプル。
Yeah, thank you, Polpol.
最初この曲を聴いて、もう役柄的にも抱えしとピエロの持つ独特な哀愁だったりとか、雰囲気もね、もうポルカ
When I first heard this song, with its unique melancholic vibe as a troubled clown,
もうそのまんまっ！ばっちりハマってたって感じでした！
it fit Polka-chan to a T, just like that!
もう本当に一緒にしてくれてありがとう、楽しかったー！
Thank you so much for doing this with me, it was so much funー!
はい、そういうことでありがとうございました。
Yeah, so thank you very much.
改めてあきちゃん、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Once again, Aki-chan, happy birthday!
そして皆さまも、本当にありがとうございましたー！
And thank you all so much as wellー!
あと他のキャスト陣の挨拶、これからのかな？
Are the greetings from the other cast members coming up next?
よし、じゃあ行ってきまーす！かかしだよね、それびょんびょんびょんびょんびょん！ありがとーーー！
Alright, well, I'm heading offー! It's Kakashi, right? Boing boing boing! Thank youーーー!
続いては、本場サバンナ出身のライオン
Up next is the lion hailing from the savannah,
じゃなくてこよてだけど、今日はライオン妹役をやってくれた博衣こよりちゃんです！こんこよー！
well, not a coyote, but Koyori, Hakui Koyori-chan, who played the role of the lion younger sister today! Konkoyoー!
はーい！ライオン兄弟役をやりました、博衣こよりでーす！イェーイ！
Haa-i! I played the lion sibling role, Hakui Koyoriー! Yay!
いやもう、去年のあき先輩の3Dミュージカルを拝見したときに、めっっちゃ感動して、元々ミュージカル大好きなので、
When I watched Aki-senpai's 3D musical last year, I was so moved, and since I've always loved musicals,
あき先輩にね、すごい長文の感想を送っちゃうぐらいだったので、今年出られてめっっちゃ嬉しかったです！楽しかった！ありがとうございました！
I ended up sending a super long essay sharing my thoughts to Aki-senpai, so I'm so, so happy I could be in it this year! It was fun! Thank you so much!
いやー、こちらこそ一緒にやってくれて本当にありがとう！もうミュージカルが好きって言ってくれてたし、こよちゃんとはね、いつかやりたいと思ってたから今回できてめっちゃ嬉しいです！
Man, thank you so much for doing this with me! You always said you loved musicals, and I've always wanted to do something with Koy-chan someday, so I'm so happy we could make it happen!
もうそれにサバンナの背景がも愛すぎてね、なんなら実家感まであったね（笑）
And the savannah background was just too lovely, it honestly even gave off hometown vibes (laughs).
いや本当に可愛くてね、最強でした！ありがとうー！嬉しいです！
She was honestly so cute, absolute perfection! Thank youー! I'm so happy!
本当に、あき先輩、お誕生日おめでとうございます！一緒にやらせていただいて、ありがとうございました！それではー！
Aki-senpai, happy birthday! Thank you so much for letting me join you! See youー!
続いてライオ、兄役をやってくれたホロライブのホワイトライオン、獅白ぼたんちゃんでーす！
Next up is Hololive's white lion who played the role of the lion older brother, Shishiro Botan-chanー!
はーい、ライオ、ライオン兄弟役を演じました獅白ぼたん です。ライオンらしく振る舞えたかな？楽しかったです！
Haa-i, I played the lion sibling role, Shishiro Botan. Did I act like a lion? I had fun!
よかったです、ありがとう！雰囲気はバッチリ合ってるのももちろん何だけど、ぼたんちゃんの普段見れないライオンっぽい仕草に萌えを感じました！ありがとう！
I'm glad, thank you! The vibe was spot-on, of course, but I felt a sense of moe from Botan-chan's lion-like gestures you don't usually get to see! Thank you!
じゃあ最後メッセージお願いします！はい、あき先輩、お誕生日おめでとうございます！参加できて嬉しかったです。バイバーイ！
Alright, please give us your final message! Yes, Aki-senpai, happy birthday! I'm so glad I could participate. Bye-bye!
続いては、ロボ子さん役をやっくれたロボットじゃなくてロボット役をやっくれたロボ子さんです！
Next up is Roboco-san, who played the role of... not a robot, but the robot role, Roboco-san!
はーい、ハロー！ロボット役をやりました、ロボ子です！
Haa-i, hello! I played the robot role, Roboco!
ロボだけにね、ほら、めっちゃ長くて難しかったんだけど、とても楽しかったです！誘ってくれてありがとう！
Since it's "Robo," you see, it was super long and difficult, but it was a lot of fun! Thank you for inviting me!
いや、見事なまでのハマり役、ロボ子さん以外本当に考えられないという役だったんだけど、ダンスもね、ロボットダンスみたいな感じ。難しいというか、まあロボットだから簡単か！一緒に踊れて歌って楽しかったです！ありがとう！
Man, it was such a perfectly fitting role, truly hard to imagine anyone else playing it besides Roboco-san. The dancing was like robot dance style too. Difficult, well, since she's a robot it's easy, huh! It was fun dancing and singing together! Thank you!
じゃあ、またね！あきちゃん、お誕生日おめでとうーーー！
Well, see you again! Aki-chan, happy birthdayーーー!
そして最後のメインキャストとして登場してくれたのは、超！超！ロックに決めていた西の魔女役の森カリオペちゃんでーす！
And appearing as our final main cast member is Mori Calliope-chan, who rocked it out super hard as the Wicked Witch of the West!
はい、ホロライブEnglishの森カリオペです。I played the part of the Wicked Witch of the West, 西の魔女でした！イエーイ！
Hi, I'm Mori Calliope from Hololive English. I played the part of the Wicked Witch of the West! Yay!
ちょっと緊張してたけど本当に頑張りました！よく見てた？どうだった？めっちゃ最高だったよ！
I was a bit nervous, but I really tried my best! Were you watching closely? How was it? It was absolute maximum greatness!
実は、この歌を初めて聴いたときに、もうカリオペちゃんが高いのステージから「うわーっ！」って歌う姿を想像してたから、今回出てくれるってなってもう本当にね、嬉しかったんだ！
Actually, when I first heard this song, I imagined Calliope-chan singing "Waaah!" from a high stage, so when it was decided she'd appear this time, I was genuinely so happy!
カリオペちゃんが登場してからは、みんないる大人数パートだったから、特にね、ワイワイガヤガヤしてもう楽しかったね！
Ever since Calliope-chan appeared, it was a large-group part with everyone there, so it was especially lively and noisy and so much fun!
そうだね！ありがと！超楽しかったね！
That's right! Thanks! It was super fun!
まあ、アキロース先輩、ハッピーバースデー！お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Well, Aki Rosenthal-senpai, happy birthday! Happy birthday to you!
今年もよろしくね！ありがとう！今年もよろしくね！
Take good care of me this year too! Thank you! Take good care of me this year too!
あの、今年ね、一緒にもっとコラボしてみたいと思いますね！
Um, I think I'd love to collaborate with you even more this year!
めっちゃ思う！嬉しい！やろう！
I totally think so too! I'm happy! Let's do it!
いろんなことに挑戦していこうね！がんばって！
Let's take on all sorts of new challenges! Do your best!